William Tallitsch

267-205-3549 bill.tallitsch@gmail.com

Profile

I am a passionate Front End Developer with years of professional experience building sites and web applications for small startups and large enterprises. I keep constantly updated on changes in the field to remain current, and my goal is to grow both personally and professionally through the success of my company and their clients.

Experience

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, IQVIA - 2017-PRESENT

I started with IQVIA working on a fairly large React internal application for a broadcast media company client. The team I was on was fairly small, but accomplished big things in the time I spent there. I enjoyed learning and working very closely with React and Redux.

For the past 2 years I have been in the Advanced Analytics department, building dashboards and other custom Enterprise solutions to manage big data and machine learning pipelines.

My current daily duties are to perform code reviews, document my code, within an agile environment. I enjoy being part of a team, and look forward to coming to work each day.

UI ENGINEER, ELSEVIER - 2016-2017

Recently I worked a six month contract on a larger development team. I worked on a number of products, including Clinical Key and Med Ed. Every day I worked with technologies such as Angular 1.x, Less, Grunt, Gulp, WebPack, jQuery, Git and JIRA. I am on a specialized squad for improving search and discovery within the Clinical Key application.

TECHNOLOGY MANAGER, NAVICOR – 2016-2017

Prior to being hired at Navicor, all digital work was being done out of the Columbus headquarters. This is an example of how much the Philadelphia office has grown, and how much trust they had in my abilities to bring knowledge and experience to the table. And though the clients are specifically Pharmaceutical and specializing in Oncology, there is certainly a fair share on innovation at our fingertips.

I currently manage two developers, as well as keeping my hands in every digital project that passes through the agency in one way or another. This means not only operations, but coding projects from start to finish myself. These projects include Native Salesforce Interactive Visual Aids, Developing and maintaining web properties, email campaigns and

rich media banner ads. Among the client facing projects are a number of internal facing interactive applications that solve long-standing problems.

Daily development duties include the use of custom-made task automation systems using Gulp, a custom SASS library, proprietary JavaScript plugins and more.

FRONT END DEVELOPER, GREY - 2015-2016

Starting at Grey was a welcomed change of pace from a severely lacking digital department, to a strong and supportive technical team. My current responsibilities cover all aspects of development support for a multitude of clients and brand teams.

My first task was to bring the studio up to speed and work closely with the developers to lead them in a modernized approach for streamlining production. This consisted of implementing new animation techniques, developing reusable and scalable templates, and teaching CLI tools for task automation.

My daily workload consistent of development within a pharmaceutical single client, among a multitude of brands, and maintaining a number of consumer-based food product web properties. I'm eager to learn and spend my free time doing research and professional training.

TECH LEAD, MCCANN REGAN CAMPBELL WARD - 2014-2015

My starting role as a Creative Front End Developer at McCann RCW, was created to expand the digital team, which until my arrival, lacked the tools for IA, rapid prototyping and front-end development. My skills in responsive and reactive web design, javaScript, HTML5, CSS3, rich media animation and UI frameworks made me an integral member of in-house project development. Some additional responsibilities included the creation of site maps and wireframes, the design and development of UX components, and facilitating quality standards in cross browser and device testing.

My responsibilities as the agency Technology Lead included technical consulting within almost all digital projects for pitches, proposals, and other presentations, as well as assisting in the creations of project scope definition and functional requirements.

SENIOR UI DEVELOPER, BRIDGE-X TECHNOLOGIES - 2012-2014

Bridge-x Connect, Customer 360 and Sales 360 are products that manage processes for companies that run SAP. As a senior UI Developer, my job is to design and develop innovative demos and prototypes for companies such as Kraft, General Mills, and

Columbia Sportswear. My time is spent on a variety of tasks that include building CSS & JavaScript modules, QA, interface design, and various web developments. Currently, I am in the process of optimizing the front end of our core foundation framework, which is built on the Spring JAVA library.

AXIOM PROFESSIONAL HEALTH, CONTRACT MULTIMEDIA DEVELOPER - 2010-2014

At Axiom, I developed Pharmaceutical E-learning applications through Adobe Flash and ultimately, within a custom built JavaScript library, in which I assisted in conceptualizing. Innovations included custom gamification components, animation and interactivity. Regular tasks included working closely with Instructional designers and project managers to adhere with clients' needs and extremely demanding deadlines.

ADMED, INC, JUNIOR MULTIMEDIA DEVELOPER - 2008-2010

As a Junior Developer fresh out of school, at AdMed, I was tasked with assisting in the design and development of Flash-based E-Learning applications. These applications required audio engineering, animations, video editing, and illustrations. Interactivity such as game-based modules, were a common aspect of these applications.

Education

Art Institute of Philadelphia – Bachelor of Science, Web Design and Interactive Media, 08

Certifications

Content Author - Adobe CQ5/Experience Manager 6, 2015

Development and QA - Google DoubleClick

Awards

Commitment Award - McCann Regan Campbell Ward, 2015

Honors - Art Institute of Philadelphia, 2008

Deans List - Art Institute of Philadelphia, 2006, 2007, 2008

Presidential Award - Art Institute of Philadelphia, 2007

Best of Quarter - Art Institute of Philadelphia, 2007, 2008

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript, PHP, working knowledge of ASP

Front End Libraries & Frameworks: Vanilla javaScript, React, Vue, Meteor, Angular 1, Greensock

Unit Testing: Jasmin, Mocha & Chai

Markup & pre-compilers: Proficient in HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, JSON, and XML

Command line tools: Node.js, NPM, Yarn, Gulp, Grunt and Bower

Database Systems: Experience with MySQL & SQLite, MongoDB

CMS: Wordpress, Drupal, Adobe CQ5/AEM6, Crown Peak

Other Languages, Libraries & Frameworks: Working knowledge of Objective-C, Swift

Version Control: Git, Mercurial, SAP NWDS DTR